Lucas Camponogara Viera

T (+886) 0979 235 851

■ monteirocamponogara@gmail.com

camponogaraviera

Currently working with design and simulation of Josephson junction-based superconducting circuits as a roadmap for large-scale fault-tolerant Quantum Computing in the NISQ era. My research interests are mainly in the field of circuit Quantum Electrodynamics and quantum-classical Machine Learnina.

Education

National Taiwan Normal University - NTNU

Taipei, Taiwan

• PHD DEGREE IN SUPERCONDUCTING QUANTUM COMPUTING

• SUBJECT: DESIGN AND SIMULATION OF CIRCUIT-BASED QUANTUM PROCESSORS FOR LARGE-SCALE FAULT-

2020 - 2023 (Exp.)

CURRENT GPA: 3.9/4.3

National Taiwan University - NTU

TOLERANT QUANTUM COMPUTING

Taipei, Taiwan

• PHD DEGREE IN SUPERCONDUCTING QUANTUM COMPUTING

2021 - present

DUAL ENROLLMENT

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• B.SC. DEGREE IN CONTROL AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE)

2017 - 2018

COMPLETED 180 CREDITS OF COMPLEMENTARY COURSEWORK IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (MACHINE/DEEP LEARNING)

• AVG: 8.04/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

M.SC. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM INFORMATION

2015 - 2017

• THESIS: DISTRIBUTION AND QUANTUM COHERENCE MANIPULATION IN MULTI-QUDIT SYSTEMS

• AVG: 7.7/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

B.SC. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

2011 - 2015

• THESIS: DIMENSIONAL ASPECTS OF PHOTON MASS IN QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

AVG: 7.59/10

Professional Experience

Research And Development Intern

NATIONAL TAIWAN NORMAL UNIVERSITY (NTNU)

Taiwan, Taipei, Sept. 2019 - Feb. 2020

• **Subject:** Development of an image deblurring-based Generative Adversarial Network with Python, Keras, and TensorFlow. Development of an algorithm for 3D-surface triangulation of a red blood cell for holographic tomography applications.

Software Engineer

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF SPATIAL RESEARCH (INPE)

Brazil, July 2017 – January 2019

• **Subject:** Hands-on expertise as a full-stack developer in GUI-based software for automated research data acquisition with Bluetooth technology.

Awards

RoboWeek Challenge

Federal University of Rio Grande, RS,

Brazil

2ND PLACE OVERALL. DEVELOPMENT OF AN ALGORITHM (C++) FOR DRIVING A TURTLEBOT INSIDE A MAZE ENVIRONMENT WITH THE AID OF LASER SENSORS. EVENT WEBSITE: HTTP://ROBOWEEK.C3.FURG.BR/

2018

MSc Scholarship Award (CNPq)

CNPQ, Brazilian Federal Research Funding Agency

FINANCIAL AID AWARD FOR SECOND-PLACE OVERALL IN MSC ENTRANCE EXAM. MINIMUM AWARD AVERAGE OF 70%.

2015

Publications ___

L. V. Camponogara, "Distribution and Quantum Coherence Manipulation in Multi-Qudit Systems," M.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2017.

L. V. Camponogara, "Dimensional Aspects of Photon Mass in Quantum Electrodynamics," B.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2014.

Viera, L. C.; Muralikrishna, P.; Schuch, N. J.; Makita, K., "Study of Ionospheric Plasma in the South Atlantic Geomagnetic Anomaly Region," INPE/CNPq 114397/2011-2, 2012.

Baseline Architectures for Convolutional Denoising Autoencoder	Taipei, Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: AUTOENCODER-BASED MACHINE LEARNING ARCHITECTURES FOR IMAGE DENOISING DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH KERAS AND TENSORFLOW. 	2020
https://camponogaraviera.github.io/Machine-Learning-Engineering/Autoencoder/	
Autoencoder - A Comprehensive Guide	Taipei, Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: INVITED TALK ON DEEP LEARNING (2H). HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/INVITEDTALK/ 	2020
Red Blood Cell 3D-Surface Triangulation	Taipei, Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: A PYTHON IMPLEMENTATION OF EVANS, E. A., AND R. SKALAK (1980) RED BLOOD CELL MODEL FOR HOLOGRAPHIC TOMOGRAPHY APPLICATIONS. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/RED-BLOOD-CELL-3D-SURFACE/ 	2019
Generator Network for a GAN-based Image Deblurring Architecture	Taipei, Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: GENERATIVE ADVERSARIAL NETWORK FOR IMAGE DEBLURRING DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH KERAS AND TENSORFLOW. 	2019
https://camponogaraviera.github.io/Machine-Learning-Engineering/GAN/	
Logistic Regression Based Facial Expression Recognition	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM FOR CLASSIFYING HUMAN FACIAL EXPRESSIONS DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING SCIKIT-LEARN. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/LOGISTICREGRESSION/ 	2018
Kinematic Algorithm for a TurtleBot in a Maze Environment	Rio Grande, RS, Brazil
 AWARD: SECOND PLACE MEDAL AWARDED TO OVERALL INDIVIDUAL TEAM WINNER OF A 24H ROBOTICS COMPETITION (ROBOWEEK CHALLENGE) AT THE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE (FURG), BRAZIL. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/ROBOWEEK-CHALLENGE/ 	2018
Sentiment Analysis using LSTM and Word2Vec	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM WITH LSTM AND WORD2VEC DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW FOR INSIGHTFUL TEXT ANALYSIS ON ATTITUDE SENTIMENT EXPRESSED IN A BLOCK OF TEXT. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/ 	2018
GUI-based Software for Automated Research Data Acquisition via a Secure Bluetooth Client-Server Channel.	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: GUI-BASED SOFTWARE FOR SENSOR DATA ACQUISITION WITH BLUETOOTH COMMUNICATION. DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH PYSERIAL. PLATFORM: WINDOWS 	2017
HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/BLUETOOTH-COMMUNICATION/	
Snake Game - MVC Standard	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/GAME-DEVELOPMENT/

Supervised Teaching in Quantum Mechanics

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

2017

2017

- INSTITUTION: FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTA MARIA
- WORKLOAD: 15H

Technical Skills _____

• Programming Languages: Python, Matlab, html5, CSS.

• DESCRIPTION: SNAKE GAME DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH PYGAME AND MVC STANDARD.

Technical Production _____

- Frameworks and Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn, Qiskit, Cirq, sympy, Pygame, OpenCV, Bootstrap.
- Others: Git, Conda, Jupyter, Linux, LATEX Sonnet®.

Languages _

• Portuguese (Native); English (ILR Level 4); Spanish (Professional working prof.); Chinese (HSK Level 2); Italian (Limited working prof.); German (Elementary prof.).

Will be pleased to provide references upon request.